SARA MUNIR

Toronto, On M8V 0J1 | 4379846134 | sara.m07011@gmail.com

Github: SaraMunir | https://saramunir.github.io/Portfolio/ | Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/sara-munir/

CAREER SUMMARY

Full Stack Web developer specializing in MERN stack technologies. Approaches to web development in a fashion that integrates mobile first and design thinking in order to create a website that manifests in enhanced digital experience for users and a robust website aligned to the client's business goals. Guided by a background in architecture, is intuitively capable of optimizing various design elements of a website's ecosystem to work together holistically.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Bootstrap, Node.js, React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Movie Maniax - https://github.com/jsanthos01/MovieManiax | https://movie-app123.herokuapp.com/

Movie Maniax is a user-friendly movie search application built on MERN stack that allows users to search for movies, add movies to watchlist as well as to favorites list. Users can also add other users as their friend and view their favourite list, watchlist and reviews.

- Utilized React for building the application's user interface
- Made use of MongoDb for database to store users information and activities in order to create, view friends lists.

Fitness Diaries - https://github.com/jsanthos01/Fitness-Diaries | https://fitness-diaries.herokuapp.com/

Fitness Diaries is a full-stack web application that uses MVC design patterns with local server-side API. The application allows users to create groups with friends and family in order to focus on achieving goals for fitness purposes.

- Made use of MySql to store and retrieve backend Data
- Utilized Javascript and Jquery to build the website

Google Books Search - https://github.com/SaraMunir/googlebooks | https://googlebooksbt2020.herokuapp.com/ Google Books Search is a React-based web application that uses local server-side API to search for books. The application allows users to View and save books in their saved page

- Used Google Books API to retrieve books
- Utilised MongoDb for database to save books and also delete them.
- Technologies used: Node, Express and MongoD

EXPERIENCE

Teleperformance Toronto, Ontario 2018 - 2019 Customer Service Associate

- Organized and reviewed warranty claims by the customers.
- Explained to customers the policies on warranties

REE ARCHITECTS Dhaka, Bangladesh 2015-2017 Associate Architect

- Prepared scale drawings and architectural designs, using computer-aided design or other tools.
- Created complex graphics and 3d modeling renderings, using independent judgment, creativity, and computer equipment.

VISTAARA ARCHITECTS - Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Dhaka, Bangladesh 2013-2015

Associate Architect

- Designed structures such as residences, office buildings in accordance with environmental, safety, or city
- Prepared information regarding design, structure specifications, materials, color, equipment, estimated costs, or construction time.

EDUCATION

University of toronto school of continuing studies, Boot Camps, Toronto, On Full Stack Web Development program

01/2020 - 04/2020

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology **Bachelor of Architecture**

Dhaka, Bangladesh July/ 2013